
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <channel>
   <title>Posts on Reading Notes</title>
   <link>http://localhost:62861/posts/</link>
   <description>Recent content in Posts on Reading Notes</description>
   <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
   <language>en</language>
   <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; 2023 - tiff</copyright>
   <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
   
       <atom:link href="http://localhost:62861/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
   
     <item>
       <title>Book 1: A Hands-On Introduction to Essential Python Libraries and Frameworks</title>
       <link>http://localhost:62861/posts/2024-07-07-a-hands-on-introduction-to-essential-python-libraries-and-frameworks/</link>
       <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>http://localhost:62861/posts/2024-07-07-a-hands-on-introduction-to-essential-python-libraries-and-frameworks/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;A book for beginners.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I purchased this book, I wanted a brief overview of the essentials, libraries I may not have heard about or had come across. Unfortunately my definition was too&amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;narrow&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;niche&lt;/em&gt; maybe because while these libraries are technically &lt;em&gt;essential&lt;/em&gt;, they are well known to anyone who has been programming for a while.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you already have familiarity with Python this may not be the book you want.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Book 2: Radware&#39;s DDoS Handbook: The Ultimate Guide to Everything You Need to Know about DDoS Attacks</title>
       <link>http://localhost:62861/posts/2024-07-07-radwares-ddos-handbook/</link>
       <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>http://localhost:62861/posts/2024-07-07-radwares-ddos-handbook/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;I finished this book in one sitting and found it an interesting insight into how blue teamers need to think about attacks. From a pentester&amp;rsquo;s perspective, it gave me a whole bunch of ideas for tooling to build.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the most interesting parts of the book was learning about Slowiris and R.U.D.Y. (R U dead yet?) DoS attacks that slowly attack a network with large HTTP requests or with extremely large form POST requests, which are hard to detect for blue teams.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I decided to try my hand on building such a tool which I&amp;rsquo;ll be making public on &lt;a href=&#34;https://projects.0x8c.run/explore&#34;&gt;my instance of Forgejo&lt;/a&gt; once it is finished.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Welcome</title>
       <link>http://localhost:62861/posts/2024-02-26-gsoc/</link>
       <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       
       <guid>http://localhost:62861/posts/2024-02-26-gsoc/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;This is just a place for me to write about the books, articles, and whitepapers I&amp;rsquo;ve read, or maybe it&amp;rsquo;s just an excuse to use a &lt;em&gt;really cool minimal Hugo theme&lt;/em&gt;. Who knows.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
     </item>
   
 </channel>
</rss>
